<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Half-bayesianism</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Half-bayesianism</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The reasonable power of the KL divergence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/2023-10-24-kulback-leibler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/2023-10-24-kulback-leibler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When doing Bayesian Inference, or any other type of inference,&#xA;chances are you have heard about &lt;strong&gt;KL divergence&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; short for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kullback%E2%80%93Leibler_divergence&#34;&gt;Kullback-Leibler divergence&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This quantity has been pervasive in machine learning and artificial intelligence and in this post I would like to explore with you, the reader, some reasons for why this is so, especially for probabilistic inference. Eventually, we&amp;rsquo;ll find ourselves dealing with Variational Inference and with a little more patience, with Expectation Propagation. But first, let&amp;rsquo;s start as usual: with a definition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My recommended research methodology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021/2021-11-01-research-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021/2021-11-01-research-methodology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fact is: research is a complex process. When done right, it is just art; when done poorly, it may have far-reaching consequences across multiple dimensions; it can bring one to a hideous spiral of psychological issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right! Let&amp;rsquo;s get down to business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all have heard people talk about the importance of time management. Rarely this subject, like proper civil education, is discussed with greater detail or practice during formal training. I, for example, never had any &amp;ldquo;formal instruction&amp;rdquo; at the university on how to organize my time around work, let alone research. It took me ages to realize that the key not just to success, but also for a happier life, was not just time management, but also &amp;ldquo;focus management&amp;rdquo;. I learnt that &lt;em&gt;it is to no avail to concentrate on time management without a proper understanding of what has to be managed using time&lt;/em&gt;. There is no amount of pomodoro&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Perhaps you have already found out about the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Pomodoro technique&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (🍅) capable to change this fact of nature!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
